- Hi everybody, Anna and Dan here
with some very exciting live show news.
Now, unfortunately, some of us are too lazy to commit
to doing a real full on tour of the UK before Christmas,
speaking about yours truly,
but that doesn't mean you can't get your fish fix.
'Cause Dan, you're not too lazy, turns out.
- Yeah, I'm gonna be on tour, everyone, around the UK.
I'm doing my first solo tour in over a decade,
and it is gonna be such an awesome night.
It's called This Changes Everything.
If you've heard my Weird Red String series,
my Mike Dan Zone obsessiveness of connecting everything,
this is a show that is perfect for you.
It's gonna be full of mind-working facts,
it's gonna have jokes, it's gonna have scary bits,
goose bump moments, please come along.
- Yes, do please make it worthwhile,
the fact that Dan's entire house is smothered
with weird sketches and strings and drawings,
freaking out the rest of his family
and any guests who come along.
He has actually told me a couple of the
extraordinary kind of plots he's weaving through this show,
and I've gotta say, it's draw-dropping stuff.
You gotta go.
And how can people go?
- So, if you wanna come along,
I'm playing places all over the UK.
I'm gonna be starting October the 11th in Edinburgh,
the Newcastle Birmingham Cardiff,
and then in November, I'm gonna be doing Manchester, Liverpool,
Cambridge, Oxford, Norwich, York Hastings, Brighton, Lester,
Bristol, Exeter, there's so many places,
all you need to do is go to thischangeseverything.co.uk
to get your tickets.
These are really cozy venues, it's like 20 quitter ticket.
I'm gonna hang around after every show,
so if you wanna say hi, just come along.
So just one more time, tickets are at thischangeseverything.co.uk
or just go to my Instagram bio, you'll find a link there.
18 dates, hopefully I can see you at one of them.
- Do it, it's a once-a-decade experience,
the dance driver, live experience.
If you remember which way to face what he's on stage,
go now, check this guy out, and for now, on with this show.
- On with the podcast.
Hello, and welcome to another episode
of no such thing as a fish, a weekly podcast
coming to you from the QI offices in Hobern.
My name is Dan Schreiber, I am sitting here
with Anatishinsky, James Harkin, and Andrew Hunter Murray.
And once again, we have gathered around the microphones
with our four favorite facts from the last seven days
and in a particular order, here we go.
Starting with fact number one, and that is Andy.
My fact is, the biggest supermarket in Europe
has 12 people whose entire job is to sort out coat hangers.
- Give me a break.
(laughing)
- 12 people.
- Yeah.
- 40 hours a week.
- Come on.
- So big.
- That's the thing, it's bigy.
- It's so big.
- How big, Andy?
- What do you mean?
- The supermarket.
- You got the coat hangers.
(laughing)
- I'm big and a, okay.
So this came from a brilliant article
by a journalist called Ralph Jones
who went to Geckas Ula Red,
which is a Swedish supermarket.
And it's a one off, right?
There's not a chain across the world.
And it's total area, including the warehouse bit,
is 114,000 square meters,
which is 20 Trafalgar squares.
It's one and a half fucking in palaces.
It is the biggest tourist attraction in Sweden.
It gets, it gets full.
- Feel brave.
- What about the housework I've used to live?
- That's not even second.
- Is it?
(laughing)
- The Viking museum we went to
doesn't even get close to it.
- That's a museum.
- Yeah.
- The ship, that's a 17th century ship
which sank on its maiden voyage.
That's the second place.
But it's second by a long distance.
- But it's, like, that's our pretty amazing.
- I think my favorite one is that every day staff can fill
about 400 trolleys of items that customers
have just discarded in different bits of the shop
to make their return journey
to where they actually belong for them.
- 400 trolleys were every single day.
- How many people must be employed full time
to fill up and move those trolleys?
Is it more or fewer than the co-hangers?
We don't know.
- That's a good point.
- But they have, like, a 10,000 item off your line.
- Yep.
(laughing)
- This place has its own reality TV show.
And I thought, oh, well, often they'll do
a little tie-in TV show.
This thing has had 11 series.
- It's incredibly popular.
It's the most watch program on Sweden's channel five.
So just to say, is this in Stockholm?
You said it was in Sweden, but--
- It's not in Stockholm.
No, it's called Ula Red.
It's a town which is, I think, quite far out.
If you were driving, it's about a five-hour journey,
I would say, roughly by car, yeah.
- It does seem to be in the middle of nowhere.
- Yeah, the town next door has a few thousand people
and this supermarket gets four million visitors every year.
I mean, I think they're okay with it.
But it is crazy.
It seems to be quite beloved.
- Do you think it's like a resident of Venice
living in that town, you know?
And you feel like it was a beautiful thing
that's been destroyed by descending.
- Oh.
- I quite like, I looked into it.
They do have a smaller supermarket in the town as well
that they can use.
- I just wonder how much action that gets versus the very one.
- I absolutely think I would only go to the supermarket.
- Yeah, no, exactly.
- You need a plate of milk.
You're not going to go to the world's largest supermarket.
- Unless you want to get your 10,000 steps up.
The bread is another 14 miles away.
(laughing)
- I always wonder about those,
'cause you hear that places use tactics,
like almost like casinos use.
You know, where casinos won't show you daylight,
they won't ever allow clocks.
They will confuse you about what direction you're facing.
They'll do these clever psychological tricks
to keep you gambler.
- Give you a load of booze.
- That's it, and I just wonder what supermarkets do.
- Well, I know, for instance,
some of them will pipe out the smell of fresh bread.
- Yes.
- On like, 'cause they'll make you hungry
and make you want to buy things.
There's also stuff about they know which direction people turn
when you go into a supermarket.
Quite often in a supermarket,
they'll put the bread as far away as you can.
So you have to, 'cause everyone is going to buy bread,
so you have to walk all the way over to get the bread.
- Past all the other good stuff, exactly.
- And they have vegetables right as you go in,
'cause that makes you think, oh, I'm in a healthy place.
- And it's got the sound that they do.
They often play slow music to make your pace slow down.
- And.
- And if you play French music around--
- Round by Forgettes and Garlic.
- They buy French wine.
- Give me a phrase.
- Yeah, that'd say the more likely to buy French wine.
If you play German music, the more likely
the buy German products, like maybe a beer.
- Does it have to be classically French music
like accordions and a classically German like--
- Yeah, if it's not funk, it wouldn't be.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Super stores out of town.
- Yeah.
- Were quite controversial when they started,
'cause the idea was that--
- Yeah, they still are.
- Yeah, the idea was that they were destroying
in-town supermarkets, which were smaller
or traditional grocery shops.
And then of course, all the little grocery shops
have gone out of business.
And now the super stores have moved back into town
doing Tesco, Metro, or whatever.
- Right, yeah.
- So they've done that.
But the first one was in Nottinghamshire in 1964,
and it was called the Window List Store.
That's how it advertised itself.
'Cause they didn't need to do shop displays to get you in.
'Cause you're ready in the shop.
- I see.
- Okay, Window List in that way.
- It's still not good marketing.
I think for me, a window list store
is gonna be very off-putting.
- Yeah, that's right.
- For most people, I think.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- You're right, you're right, you're right, you're right, you're right.
- Also, if you want to buy some windows.
- Yeah.
(laughing)
- Sorry, we're a window list store.
- I'll never go to Tesco for my windows,
so it'd be fair.
- But the shopping centers, like Andy said,
they got people out of the town centers,
and that's why if you go to any town center
in the north of England,
it's just baked shops and bedsy shops, because- - Also, 'cause of the internet.
- Oh, sadly.
- Also 'cause of the internet, but also, can I say,
because of feminism?
- Oh, well, we have a lot of forms of forms.
- Okay, floor is yours, Andy, please.
(laughing)
- This is really interesting.
So it is slightly to do with increasing employment for women,
especially after the Second World War, right?
Which is when you're starting to get the rise of the supermarkets.
So more women are going out to work,
and that means that families no longer rely
on one person in a household being at home,
and therefore being able to go out and shop every day
for that evening's meal.
Suddenly, people are at work,
and they're needing to do a weekly shop,
and that means bigger shops,
so there's more of an appeal there,
and the other thing is that people are getting fridges,
due to labesafing devices, due to feminism.
And- (laughing)
That means that you can store more of your food, of course.
And so you're much more tempted to say,
all right, I'll just go to the mega-mart all of a weekend
and do my shop later.
- Yeah, I'm sorry.
We're to blame for the fridge and so much more.
What can I say?
(laughing)
I found a similar supermarket to this one,
but that I think is my favorite,
called Jungle Jim's International Market.
- Okay. - Do you guys know this?
- Yeah, yeah.
- So this has a claim to be the largest supermarket
in the world, it's in Fairfield, Ohio,
and it's a really good American Dream Story,
'cause it was set up by a guy called Jim Bonominho in 1971,
who literally borrowed someone's truck for the weekend
to have a fruit and vegetable in a parking lot,
worked 21 hour days and showered under a hose pipe
that was in the car park.
And now it's this gigantic,
maybe the biggest supermarket in the world,
over six acres, has America's biggest wine selection,
it's got live seafood tanks in it,
but he's so great, I've read an interview with him
by the Wall Street Journal and he came down dressed
as a wizard and the interviewer said,
did you wear that 'cause he knew you were being interviewed
and he said, no, I calmed it down a bit for you,
usually I'd wear something much weirder.
And he was just mad, like at one point the interviewer said,
perhaps the most important question,
maybe the hardest question of all.
And he said, hold on, we're under the hardest question,
let me get up my crystal ball
and got a natural crystal ball out from under the table.
And he was thinking he needs to brand better,
'cause that's not what someone who lives in a jungle would do.
I feel like he should have come to the interview
swinging down on a vine with like tidy,
you're right. - That's skin, trunks on.
- Maybe he does that for the New York Times.
But they sell incredible stuff,
I've got a whole aisle of adult-oriented hot sauces,
goats heads and pigs heads they sell,
interesting full packaging, full pig's head,
just staring up at you,
an eight-foot-long gummy snake
in the sweet section, could you eat that?
- For sure, I love gummies.
- Eight-foot-long, you could eat.
- Well, what's the girth?
(laughing)
- It's a millimeter.
- You're fine, you actually get less gummies
than in a normal one.
(laughing)
- That is big, that is big.
- That's big.
- It's a big gummy snake.
- I think James could do it.
I've seen him on tour.
- I would, I would be like an actual snake eating,
'cause you'd have to just open your mouth
and stuff it in and then sit there
for a month waiting for it to die.
- You're the gummy deer who's eating the gummy snake.
It's a nice, reversey Percy.
- Lovely.
- Yeah.
- When was the first self-checkout opened?
What year?
Quiz time?
- 1956.
- The first.
- 4,000 BC.
(laughing)
- Well, it's a powerful disappointment on Andy's snake.
2010.
- Oh, I don't think you idiot.
(laughing)
- It's 1986.
I was surprised that the electronic self-checkout,
which I and he really became aware of in about 2010.
- Where was it?
- Jar Jar.
- George.
- Oh, one supermarkets.
- The ex-Selviet country.
Find the south of your accent.
(laughing)
- Yeah.
- That's right, Stalin's homeland.
- Yep.
(laughing)
- Oh, sorry, Georgia and America.
- That is surprising.
- Right.
- But the reason they're not good self-checkouts
is that if you're involved in a transaction,
it seems to you to go faster.
And this is a psychological thing called weight warping.
- Yeah.
- You know, if I'm having to hand over the stuff,
then...
- Yeah, and if I'm putting through my pot pies,
and I'm trying to make it beep and it doesn't beep,
and I do it five times and it's still not beeping,
I get a little bit annoyed,
but if someone else is doing that, I'm like,
come on, get on with it.
- Yes, you're right.
And in fact, it's the reason why it's good to use
a self-checkout, because it goes faster for you.
Yes, yes, yes, sorry, yeah.
- Very cool.
- But we don't actually have them
because it seems faster for us.
We have them so that supermarkets don't have to employ
any humans.
- That's a great thing.
- That's very cynical.
- I'm dreadfully sorry.
(laughing)
I would say there's another contender
for first self-checkout,
which we've actually never talked about before,
but we've talked about the inventor.
- 1956.
- You're really close.
It's 1937.
- Oh, wow.
- And it's found by Clarence Saunders.
And if you guys remember him,
invented Piggly Wiggly, which is a supermarket
that we talked about.
He invented Piggly Wiggly in 1916.
- So Piggly Wiggly was like the first store
where you went in with a trolley
and put stuff in your trolley, right?
- Yeah, or a basket, the first self-service.
So usually you'd meet the member of staff
and then you'd say what you wanted
and the staff would go and get it for you.
And Piggly Wiggly was like,
you know what, the people could pick their items themselves.
- It was an amazing idea.
- Incredible idea.
And everyone hastes it felt to them
like they were shoplifting.
- Oh, I thought that's what people might like it.
It's a bit of a treat.
- A bit of a different.
- I think at the start people rebelled against it
a little bit and thought this is interesting.
- They did keep forgetting to pay.
- But do you know what inspired him
to create Piggly Wiggly?
- What?
- He was looking out of a train one day
and he saw some pigs rushing towards a trough
and he thought, wow, what a metaphor.
Maybe those pigs could be the people in my shop.
I think what is the idea?
- And then this guy went on a few years later and...
- Yes, and he made caduzzle.
- Which some people think stand for or meant key does it all.
Which makes sense because it was fully automated in that
you went into the grocery shop
and everything was under these sort of like glass domes.
And you had your own key and when you got to an item
you wanted you inserted a key in a slot
and the key had a ticker tape on it
and you go around inserting your key
into lots of different slots saying,
I want this object, I want this object.
And then you took it to the till
and you gave it to a person who inserted your ticker tape
into a machine which then could see all the things
you'd said you wanted and then the machine automatically
went and picked up your groceries
and slid it down a conveyor belt towards you.
It was fantastic.
- And did he get this idea from seeing a lot of pigs
using a vending machine?
(laughing)
- He did, yeah.
And much like the pigs using a vending machine
it didn't work very well.
- It's an amazing innovator.
He was just missing one person really in his life
and that's someone who could think of a decent name.
- That's clearly...
- I think that was the problem.
- Pigly Wiggly.
- What's the other?
- Conduza Luzzi.
- I think the problem was that everyone
got the wrong stuff all the time
'cause he didn't quite perfect it
which is annoying when in a shop.
- So coat hangers.
- Yeah.
- Who invented them?
- Someone you've heard of.
- George Coat Hanger.
(laughing)
- Ben Franklin.
- Someone famous.
- Ben Franklin is about as close as you're going to get.
- Thomas Jefferson.
- Correct.
- No.
- According to the Paris Museum of Fashion,
he invented them.
Although according to the Monticello website,
which was his home,
there's no evidence that he invented them at all.
But for sure, we invented coat hangers sometime
in the 18th century, but they didn't catch on.
And it wasn't until the 1850s that they became popular.
Thanks to Friend of the Podcast,
the burgeoning middle class.
(laughing)
- We've got to get them on the next
Friend of the Podcast TV show.
- Really?
- And the disappearance of domestic servants.
So they met the people who were buying more clothes
and they had to put them somewhere
and they didn't have someone to iron them up.
Then the wire coat hanger was invented
by someone called Albert J. Parkhouse in 1903.
And he was working in a wire company.
They made like novelty wires, it said.
But the company didn't have enough coat hooks
for people to put their coats on.
And so we took a discarded piece of wire
from the machinery and turned it into the shape
of someone's shoulders and said, we could do this.
But according to his granddaughter,
who's called Barbara Mussel, he didn't make any money from it
because the company took the patent,
sold a gazillion wire coat hangers
and he never made a penny.
- Right.
- He was Mussel though.
- Yeah, as the name of his granddaughter's husband,
presumably, came at that wedding.
He must have heard the name of that guy and thought,
oh my God, this puts my whole life into perspective.
(laughing)
- Do you miss the muscle?
- He's basically part of the altar of it.
- I think some inventions are so good
that you shouldn't be able to patent them.
- Yeah.
- And then if we had to pay a quarter of a penny
to the guy who invented the coat hanger
every time we bought one.
- I mean, technically, you do.
- Yeah, yeah, that's how capitalism works.
- Well, I don't pay anything for my coat hanger.
So I get the free from the dry cleaner.
- Stop stealing the hair!
- I get mine free from hotels,
but it's really annoying
'cause they don't have the hook better than the hook.
- You've got to take the whole wardrobe with you
so you have a complete pain in the ass.
(laughing)
(upbeat music)
- Okay, it's time for fact number two and that is Anna.
- My fact this week is that the latest winner
of the Nobel Prize in literature wrote a novel
in 2024 that was one sentence long.
- That shot?
- Yeah, that's all you need to do to get it.
Just write a sentence.
No, it was actually a really long sentence.
- It was 400 pages long, more than 400 pages.
Yeah, this is a guy called Lashlow Crashner Hawkeye.
He's Hungarian.
I haven't read anything of him.
My brother's read a couple, says he is a challenge.
- I've read a few pages of one of his books this week.
- Oh, yeah.
- And it's dense.
- It's hard to go in.
- Even just looking at it.
It's like blocks of text.
And the one I read which is called Satan Tango
does have quite a lot of sentences in it,
but they are all very long.
- That was actually the one I think my brother likes.
- Yeah, it's objectively good.
- The idea seemed good.
I picked one up this morning.
There's one called Hersht 07769.
And it opens with him the character writing a letter
to the Chancellor Angela Merkel
'cause he's convinced the big bang is going to be reversed.
- So this is the one that's the one long sentence.
And apparently the opening, if that was what you read,
it starts, hope is a mistake.
And I think this might be--
- That's a sentence.
I believe it then goes on.
I don't think there's a full stop at the end.
I think it's hope is a mistake.
And it just uses the word and a lot.
- Also, semicolon's cover a multitude of sins.
- They do, although I don't know how many semicolon's
he's using and he says it's 'cause he wants to mimic
human speech.
- Which I think is a very good and interesting point.
People don't speak in short declarative sentences.
Usually they pause, they deliberate,
their words flow.
You see, I'm doing it now.
And he composes it all in his head
and then he only writes it down when he's ready,
which I think is crazy.
- What?
- That must be so hard.
I don't think the whole novel.
- But yeah, right.
- The feeling of it, yeah.
- He has something in common with the man
who invented Piggly Wiggly.
- Okay.
- He was inspired for his first novel
by a load of pigs in a field.
- Yes. - No.
- Yes. - Really?
- Wow. - Oh my god.
- So he had a load of jobs.
He grew up in Hungary, Cold War Hungary.
And he had a load of different jobs.
He was a minor for a while.
- We were all minor for a while.
(all laughing)
- But I walk into these stupid jokes.
- Stupid jokes.
- No, that's a spirit.
I'd be surprised. - Thanks for your encouragement.
(all laughing)
- And then he was a night watchman
for a herd of cows briefly.
And then he got to the house.
- No, that's not a job.
(all laughing)
- No farmers asked him to do that.
- Father comes in, yeah.
They've been asleep all night.
(all laughing)
- Okay, look at it.
It's no podcaster, but it was with the work
that was going in Soviet Hungary.
And then he got a job working on a farm,
holding piglets in place to be castrated.
- Oh.
- And he just said this was a horrible job.
- They would have been wiggly piglies.
And he realized he sympathized very deeply
with these piglets.
These poor piglets were to be very interesting.
- Losing their knackers.
And he said he wanted to write about the world
in a deep way as a result of that job.
- Wow.
- We get to read him because of his translators, right?
And he's had a few, but the most recent one
is this lady called Ottely Mullsett.
But she seems to be just his general translator
because Anna, the article that you sent to us,
which was a New Yorker article that had his story,
all of his answers were translated by her.
So even his interviews are translated by Ottely.
And she says sometimes it can take up to three years
to translate because you're translating a single sentence.
You need to make it work.
And it's really dense and it's really hard.
- But not surely not an interview for the New Yorker
where they've got to go to press at the end of the week, actually.
- Honestly, give me three years.
- Honestly, the interview's as long as one of his books
and as intense.
One of the opening questions the interviewer talks about
is Nobel Prize speech.
And he says, "You thank your brother.
You're all the brother for lifting you on his shoulders
when you were children because he taught you
that there could be another way of looking at the world.
What did you see up there?"
And he said, "At first, nothing.
My older brother got angry at me
because up there on his shoulders
something frequently happened in my little trousers.
It was not so pleasant for my brother.
He would shake me in his anger
and then I couldn't see too much of the world.
Now that we're both very old,
I asked how awful it was for him."
He says, "I still feel it."
- The urine is the--
- Driggling down his neck.
- I think we're talking about a hardened state.
- Oh, are we?
'Cause I thought you're in a first--
- Oh, you're in?
- Are you sure it's not urine?
- Wow.
I've got to see my shrink.
(all laughing)
- I just booked that, you guys keep talking, I'm just so--
- When he's on?
- Hey, he's up in the get.
- Don't worry, we added the show, it's fine.
I'm sure James will help me out tomorrow, it's good.
- My mom's fine, yeah.
No, she's great.
- Looking hot as ever.
(all laughing)
Okay, it's good to see you.
Bye, yeah.
Sorry, guys.
When you said he thanked his brother for lifting him up
on his shoulders so he could see the world,
I assumed of course that was a metaphor.
But then if you say, "And I passed on his shoulders"
all worse while I was up there,
it actually is lifting me up on his shoulders.
So I could, 'cause you know what,
I've been standing on the shoulders of giants.
I assumed for years that that was a metaphor.
- No, no.
- No, no, no.
- I just, I just, I just literally got piggybacks
from everyone in the scientific establishment.
(all laughing)
- Anyway, long sentences.
- Yeah, long sentences. - There's long sentences.
Why quite like is all the record holders for long sentences?
Aren't like silly gimmicky people,
their great writers like Fulkner held the record
for a long time, he got the Guinness World Record in 1983?
- James Joyce did a lot of long sentences.
- He did, but not as long as Fulkner's in Absalom, Absalom.
- I tell you what, he nearly got a long sentence
after the, you know, insanity trial and so on
under which he was these was banned in the early 20s.
- Good one. - Good one.
- Tough to Google long sentences, isn't it,
when you're doing research?
'Cause you get a lot of penal stuff.
Not that kind of--
(all laughing)
- That's what I'm doing.
- Anyway, Fulkner, 1288 words.
That was the longest sentence in literature,
an Absalom Absalom.
Which I haven't actually read,
but just thinking of post-modern literary techniques,
one of my favorite books is His Sound and the Fury,
where he wanted it to be printed in lots of different colors.
Have you guys ever read it?
- No.
- It's incredible, but it's quite unclear
who's narrating it sometimes.
There's like a tangle of narrations.
And he wanted-- - You should write, said,
George, if only thought of that.
(all laughing)
- I don't want to give too many tips to the greats,
but sometimes--
- No, I wish he was for the life to his,
to your suggestion.
He wanted all the different people
to have the font in different colors.
And finally, they couldn't afford
the publishing cost at the time,
but they released a special edition a few years ago,
which I now own of William Fulkner's Sound and the Fury
and all the different colors of the rainbow.
- And does it assist the reading experience?
I guess it makes it clearer.
- Yes, it does.
- Wow.
- Sentences are getting shorter.
- Are they?
- Yeah.
(all laughing)
- Just in that little conversation.
- What, generally?
- So this is in New York Times best sellers.
There was great piece in the economist,
analyzing sentence length between 100 years ago and now.
And sentences have lost one third of their weight, their heft.
They've gone from about 22 words on average, to 15.
And Victorian sentences were thumbingly long.
You read a Victorian novel.
The sentences are just longer.
There's more being expressed in each individual.
- It's Hemingway, isn't it?
What did it?
- Yes.
- And all well.
- Bloody Hemingway.
- But wasn't it true, like, have we said this before,
that Hemingway supposedly lost one of his transcripts,
but needed to deliver it like two weeks later.
And so had to rewrite the thing.
And then thought, oh my God,
I'm not gonna be able to write it the way it was.
I'm just gonna write really short sentences,
'cause it's easy to do.
- I can't remember any of the adjectives or adverbs I use.
So I'm just gonna strip all of those out.
It was just the man hunted the fish.
And then I'll do those later.
Also, he sent that off to his publishers
and like, I'm gonna send the adjectives
in a second pack.
(all laughing)
In case they get lost.
I feel like that's at least a story that's told about him.
- I love this tree.
- I heard that.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- But yes, they have.
Although I wonder about other languages,
because all these studies are always done
about the English language.
I mean, it's very hard to research other languages.
All I could find is speculation that French,
actually, the sentences haven't really got shorter
and actually, in literature, they're getting longer.
Some people were saying, but it's hard to work it out.
- Yeah.
The Nobel Prize for Literature,
there's a fantastic list, obviously, on Wikipedia,
where you can see every winner.
And there's a photo with every winner as well.
And that is so worth looking at,
because the first six or seven people,
all of them somehow look like a dog
that's been shampooed and blow dried.
Their hair is just, it's marvelous.
It's, yeah, highly recommend going to look at it.
- Well, you're not looking at the winner of Croft's.
(all laughing)
- Oh, look at Peter.
- I did have that tab open at the same time.
I'll go back and look.
The early days, Sully Proudholm is the first winner.
I personally have never heard of Sully.
I only know them as the first winner of the Nobel Prize for Literature.
- And there was a lot of controversy.
As far as I can tell, there was a lot of newspapers saying,
where's Tolstoy at the time and why did this guy get it?
And I think the prizes have always had that.
But then we do have big names that you would recognize.
There's Samuel Beckett, of course.
Waiting for Goddo was his big play,
but he wrote novels as well.
And one of them was called How It Is.
It has no punctuation.
And the entire story is a guy just trawling through mud,
trying to just get somewhere and remembering his old life.
Sounds awesome.
Sounds fantastic.
- I do think sometimes they wouldn't kill them
to give it to a mystery or a thriller writer.
Just to someone who's done a really good crime reveal.
- Stephen King.
- Where's his, yeah.
- Where's the Nobel, you know, for--
- It's the Nobel.
- Where's the Agatha Christie Nobel for Literature?
Like that was a cracking plot where actually it was his brother
all along.
(all laughing)
But he thought he was lost at sea,
but actually he was found in a mine.
- They come in other prizes.
- But this is for high literature, right?
- 2017, I reckon you're like Andy, it was Isha Guru.
- Casua Isha Guru.
And he wrote what was his book, The Remains of the--
- Yeah.
- And he was the day.
- Incredible book, right?
- Wonderful books.
- So he did win it.
Do you know what he did before he got into books?
- Isha Garo.
- Yeah.
- Here come him.
- I don't remember.
- He doesn't take link code hangers.
He was a grouse beater for the Queen Mother at El Moro.
- Disgusting.
(all laughing)
- Now for American listeners, we should say.
- No grouse hurt.
Well actually lots of grouse get hurt really badly,
but not through the beating.
- Well that's a start of it.
So you're scaring them to fly up in the air
and then they get shot.
- Exactly, and then they get shot.
- And then they go shot.
But you're beating the, whatever it is.
- The bush.
- Beating the bush.
- You'll be seeing about the bush.
You're beating the undergrowth that they're in
to scare them up.
- To scare them up.
- Sorry, Casua Isha Guru was a grouse beater
for the Queen Mother.
- Yeah, that makes me reevaluate.
- Casua Isha Guru, I have to say.
- Why?
- I don't know, I didn't know who's from that kind of stock.
- I don't think you have to be.
- Is the grouse beater usually one of the royal family?
- Yeah, usually the Earl of our girl
or something you really said.
- Well done.
- It's not, no not lately.
- Do you know something you'd be quite posh
to be beating the Queen Mother's grouse?
(all laughing)
- So layered and innuendo.
- But what are we really talking about?
- Speaking of the history of some Nobel Prize winners,
Gabrielle Garcia Marquez, who wrote 100 years of solitude
as well as many other things, but that's the main one.
And do you know what his favorite song was?
- Manbow number five.
- It's correct.
- What?
- No.
- But not that version.
- 100%.
(all laughing)
- Oh yes, and Anna's right.
The Lou Baker or the original?
(all laughing)
- It was original.
- Oh, that's very cool.
- Oh wow.
- But wait, that's only because Marquez
probably didn't live to hear the Lou Baker version.
Which is infinitely superior.
- Oh no, the Bob the Builder version.
- That's the height.
- Well, did you know that when it goes one, two, three, four, five,
it actually goes all the way up to 100 years of solitude.
No.
(clapping)
So when he, in his memoir,
he wrote about when he was a young man,
he lived in a brothel in Barranquilla.
And that's when he learned to write,
and he would dance the night away.
And he keeps saying that his favorite song is
manbow number five.
- It's stunning.
- The way Paris Prada.
- Really good.
- It's stunning.
- If you lived in a brothel,
you probably would have a little bit of moniker
in your life, a little bit of Jessica Bayer's side.
- Yeah.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, it is time for fact number three.
And that is James.
- Okay, my fact this week is that Zebras don't get ulcers,
but Zebrafish might.
- Mmm.
- Mouth ulcers or stomach?
- We're talking stomach ulcers.
- Ooh, okay.
- But I'm gonna roll back on this all quite quickly.
- Okay.
- Okay, so this is about a paper that I read
from the journal Brain Behavior Evolution
by Bianca Fusani and Ruey F. Oliveira.
And their title refers to a book
called Why Zebras Don't Get Ulcers, my Robert Sapolsky.
And he says that animals don't get chronic stress
because if you're a deer being attacked by cheetah,
you get really, really stressed for a few seconds,
but then afterwards you kind of forget about it.
- Right.
- And then you might get stressed again
and then you forget about it.
- But you don't worry.
Then Zebra's lying awake at night thinking,
"I'm really hungry."
- Exactly, we're at cheetahs.
- When we make a very, very minor faux pas,
we lie at bed at night thinking,
"Oh my God, what did I do?"
Or when we know we've got something coming up,
we worry about it.
And that's a chronic stress,
which people used to think caused ulcers.
And now we know it doesn't cause ulcers,
but does exacerbate them.
And so the paper was actually about zebrafish
and whether zebrafish do get chronic stress
and they are arguing that they do
and they use this whole zebra's don't get ulcers
because it's a famous book.
They use that as the title of the...
- And is it like a self-help book?
Is it saying, well, zebra's don't get stressed?
- Exactly.
- There's no reason for you to.
- Bemo zebra.
- Zebrafish are amazing, by the way.
- Sure are.
- They are known as the mice of water
because basically scientists are able to do so much testing on them
because they've got 70% genetic similarity to humans.
So we have used them in so many different ways
in order to learn about ourselves
in the way that we use mice.
That's pretty amazing.
- You know when people say that,
we know that we've got 60% genetic similarity
to bananas, right?
- Yeah.
- So when people are like,
"Oh, they're known as the mice of the fruit bowl."
- That's true.
(laughing)
- But no, they're kind of not just genetically,
they're kind of body is built quite similar to us.
So that art is quite similar.
Their brains are quite similar.
- Inside, I'm from the outside.
They don't look that similar.
- No, but on the inside.
- Much smaller.
- And also they're really useful
'cause they lay transparent eggs
and they have transparent larvae, right?
Which seems to be quite a key thing.
So it means that researchers don't need to get X-ray vision
to watch what's happening inside them when they test them.
So they'll give them an infection
and you can just use the telescope.
- A telescope or a microscope?
- That's where the eggs are.
- Yeah.
- They always send them to the moon actually to do the studies.
- Well, you say it's just in the larvae,
but this is one of the extraordinary things
about the zebrafish.
We have genetically modified the fish
to create a new fish, which is called the Casperfish.
The Casperfish, I guess, like the friendly ghost,
it's see through.
So they've basically mutated two different genes
so that as they get into adulthood,
they stay transparent.
- Yeah.
- And so you can see their heart work
in presumably unlikely.
- Exactly.
- Is it a camouflage thing for the eggs to be transparent?
I think I read that, that it's useful.
So the other fish can't see your eggs as easily and eat them.
- Makes sense?
- Yeah.
- You're a vegetable, aren't you?
- God, that makes it even worse than
that we've created out of zebrafish,
another new type of fish, the glowfish.
Have you seen the glowfish?
- No.
- Okay, so basically scientists were taking
green phosphorescent protein out of things
like jellyfish and they were putting it into zebrafish.
And what it meant was if you turn out the lights,
they glow, right?
And this has changed everything if any of them
go back into the wild for the fact that they can't hide anymore
'cause they're literally a beacon of light in the ocean.
- I can't believe they put them back in the water.
That seems mad.
- I think you shouldn't do that.
- I think they wouldn't, but they do put them in fish tanks
'cause they sell them commercially.
So if you happen to have another fish
that was a bit predatory or even in the fish tank,
it's got no chance of hiding.
- I can't even hide in the little castle or the skull.
- I also think if you have two fish and one of them
is a predator of the other,
probably keep them in two bowls.
- Yeah, you would think.
- If you've got a lionfish and you've got a zebrafish,
it will end very poorly.
- It's a very good, yeah.
- Well a lot of people don't do their research.
It's mad that this exists, I think.
I don't think it harms the fish itself,
but you can get them in starfish red,
moonrise pink, sunburst orange.
There's a whole.
- Yeah, it's fascinating.
- It's Frankenstein, isn't it?
- It's very, yeah, it's very hot.
- I definitely know people who've had aquarium fish
where they get a bunch of aquarium fish
and one fish eats all the others.
I think that might be quite a common mistake
that fish buyers get.
So yes, do your research.
- It's a common mistake that fish sellers
sound like they're making.
- Yes, you're right.
- It's not a mistake for them.
They get to sell five more fish
when the other ones get eaten.
- It's a racket.
- So is there a fish whether they get stressed on that?
When they're attacked and they get stressed for that reason,
they will swim into a nice, worn area of water.
And this is really interesting.
It's basically, they call it an emotional fever.
So your body can metabolize things better when you're warmer.
And that's why when you are sick, you get a fever
because your body heats up
and a lot of the mechanisms that will help you get better,
work better.
But what they do because they can't increase their own temperature,
they'll swim to a warmer bit of water
which heats up their entire body
and then can speed up like the tissues being repaired
and stuff like that.
- Wow.
- So they make their own fever when they're stressed.
- If you're in the bath, if you're real.
(laughing)
- Yes.
- You'll get better faster.
- Or if your child is feeling sick,
just sit another child on top of the head
and allow them to wield them.
- They test antidepressants on them.
So they do get depressed.
And this is because--
- Zebra fish.
- Zebra fish get depressed, yes.
And you can tell the person is depressed
because it swims lower down in its tank.
And that's literally the way.
So you can tell if antidepressant is working
that you've tried on it,
because it suddenly starts swimming high up in the tank.
And do you know how they get them depressed
in the first place?
- Is it reading them the works of Lajlo,
Kraslo, short drive?
(laughing)
- It's more basic than that.
They get them drunk
and then they let them have a hangover.
- Oh.
- They feed them alcohol for a few weeks
and then they cut off their supply
and then they get depressed.
- That's amazing.
You know they've been flying a space since the '70s?
- On their own.
- Mm-hmm.
- Nope.
- With astronauts.
- The mice of space.
- The mice of space, they kind of are.
- They kind of are, Andy.
- Yeah, 'cause in 2024,
four Zebra fish were up in space.
That was one of the most,
there might have been one mission since,
but this is the most notable one recently
'cause they survived 43 days.
The longest any fish has ever survived in space.
They went through a huge selection process.
So these four were whittled down from 200 candidates
and managed to get up there.
They don't live long, so for them 43 days
is about four years in space.
- Oh wow.
- So that's how we see the change
in what's going on with them.
So they're very useful.
But then this is a bit shocking.
They don't bring them back.
They just pop them in a sort of,
- Not out of the airlock.
- Well they put a pop them in some kind of container
and they just let it burn up on entry back into space.
- Oh no.
- Yeah, they're very least stick them in a saucepan
which you hang out of the spaceship.
- What, so they float away?
- So you'll have a delicious fish supper
by the time you get you land.
- Oh, nice, sorry.
- Right.
- And these things are about three cents of each
as it land.
- They're the ones that you're in the case, yeah.
- But the better than mice in space in theory
'cause they don't have solid pooes
that go rolling around everywhere
or floating around everywhere.
And they don't have gas that escapes the fish bowl.
So apparently they're just a better--
- They must have some kind of poo though.
- Yeah, yeah.
Why would mice, sorry, you're saying mice farts
of problems in space.
- Big problem, if you're not read the,
or the do's read something.
- What's happening?
- Wait, my ass, this is floating further and further away.
- But if they did have solid pooes,
they're living in water.
The pooes are gonna be in the water.
They're not gonna disappear around the--
- Yes, I think that's--
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- And you figured the mice would be in a container as well
that would mean it wouldn't escape.
So what's going on, NASA?
(laughing)
- Lot of questions.
I actually had an insanely stressful moment
just before coming into the office today.
I was getting on the tube
and there was a 70 year old man on a wheelchair,
and he was--
- How did you know how old he was?
- He counted the brakes.
(laughing)
- He had a luring, he had a bad, yeah.
- He got off the tube, the door's closed,
but the balloon was stuck inside and he just flew down the,
oh, it was, it was worse for me than him.
I'm gonna tell you, it's, I can't tell you what that.
No, he was, he was in a wheelchair.
He looked roughly 70 years old
and we came up to the escalator and I went down.
I thought, oh, there's a lift over there,
but he thinks it might be here.
And then I was watching him and he turned around.
- Oh, crubs.
- And he went backwards down the escalator.
It was amazing.
- Yeah.
- He put two hands on each of the--
- Oh, wow.
- Oh, I see that.
- Yeah, and I was watching the big wheel
and it looked like it was teetering over the edge
and the stress was actually less,
are you gonna hurt yourself?
'Cause I assume he knew what he was doing.
But if he did fall, I was, I was in his back.
- He'd be like Indiana Jones.
(all laughing)
- Is that a scene in the damage range?
- With the giant ball coming chasing him.
- But it would be a scene.
- Exactly 70-year-old, man.
(all laughing)
- I was horrible.
I mean, stress is a fascinating feeling
because you get over it.
I was, by the time I was off the escalator, it was gone.
- I can't believe this.
I can't believe you've crowbared that anecdote.
- Well, it just happened to me.
- It's so relevant.
A life experience, just before we talk about stress.
- I'm not going to bring it up.
I don't know if you were stressed by that.
And also your takeaways.
Stress just disappears, isn't it?
It's a pretty way.
I think I'm saying it doesn't.
- Well, that was done as a equivalent
of being chased by a lion.
- Yes.
- No, you've treated stress like we're supposed to
rather than holding on to it.
- Yeah, I've got a question.
Did you, when you got that sort of stress hormone
in your body, did you do the fight or the flight?
'Cause that's what happens, right?
You know, that's the idea.
- Did you punch him in the face?
(all laughing)
- That's the idea invented by a guy called Walter Cannon.
Sounds so much like Water Cannon.
(all laughing)
- It was brilliant.
- Just with an extra L.
But now these days, we've gone from the 2Fs to the 6Fs.
So you can have fight, flight, freeze,
fawn, fine, or faint.
Sounds like you have fine.
- Fine.
- As if it was fine.
- It was fine.
- No, it was fine.
I had something.
- Fawn, as in bowing and scraping and all kinds of things.
- Yeah, so yeah, exactly.
- It's like when you're in a stressful situation,
rather than running or fighting,
you try and almost calm things down.
- You apologize.
- You just run the person, that's my method.
- And then fein is like, you pretend you're okay,
presumably, but what's, what's feint?
- That's feint, it was.
- A feint with an E or an A.
- With an A, so it's like, you just collapse as if,
almost good. - Is that a useful response?
Well, people do do that.
If you're in very stressful situations,
you might just go completely catatonic
and not respond to it kind of.
- But these feel like really not useful.
Like, fight or flight is a useful thing
if you've got a line attacking you,
but is it useful to collapse or to say I'm fine?
- Yeah. - You're playing dead, I suppose.
- Yeah.
- And fine is just ignoring the problem,
which there are definitely adaptive reasons for that.
Imagine. - Yeah.
- We have the most amazing way
of measuring stress levels now.
So, as we've said, raised cortisol is stress.
I could find out from James,
how stressed you've been at different times of the year
over the past year.
- Okay, how?
Can you hear me now?
- I need some equipment and I need to be a scientist.
I'm not bending over for that.
(laughing)
- Come on.
- Is it a part of James that it's been left in?
- Yes.
And you can actually tell much better on me.
You could tell a much longer period of time on me.
How is it my breast milk?
(laughing)
- You're not producing much these days, are you?
- I'm very stressed.
(laughing)
- I suppose I'll kill this,
getting game crinkly.
I have longer hair than you guys.
Cortisol goes into our hair.
The way now that scientists study stress levels
and what causes human stress is they look at their hair
and the cortisol levels.
And you can see it's a bit like ice cores are used
to tell climate over time.
And you can see about a period of 12 months.
And so they've studied, for instance, the fact that
people stress levels peak in winter, we know.
And if they take care from people
who live in nice equatorial countries,
there's not nearly as much cortisol
in the winter segment of their hair,
which was growing in winter.
Compared to in Norway, for instance,
where there's much more stress.
- And that's like how lots of tropical trees
don't actually have very strong rings in the middle.
- It's just like that.
- Because they've got the same climate all year round.
- That these people are the tropical trees
of the human world.
- That's crazy.
- Wow, wow, so cool.
So yeah, I could just plug a hair from your head
and tell you that three months ago,
you were really stressed about something.
And you could get...
- And it was probably my hair transplanted.
(laughing)
- But that's a good point, isn't it?
- This isn't working out.
- Oh, yeah.
- Some dicker keeps plugging my hair out.
- It doesn't go into all your hairs.
- No, just one.
- No, but if they...
(laughing)
- Sorry.
- It's ages to find out.
- I'm just thinking about other parts of the body.
- I'm thinking 'cause I don't know...
I don't know if they used your ass hair for the...
(laughing)
- Well, I've a lot quite a few things.
- It's very luxurious.
(laughing)
- And now have a look at this.
He did bend over.
(laughing)
(upbeat music)
- Okay, it's time for our final fact of the show.
And that is my fact.
My fact this week is that the world record holder
of most bug tattoos is terrified of bugs.
- That's so silly.
- Yeah, well, it's...
- Why's it done that?
- Um...
- So he's trying to increase his stress levels.
(laughing)
- Yeah, exactly.
- So he's got 864 insects tattooed on his body.
Not all bugs, by the way.
So when they were doing the Guinness World Records count,
they had to discount a bunch because they were...
- A rac-nid.
- A rac-nid, you know?
There were millipedes on there.
They don't count, so it's a, it's a, it's a, come on.
That's what it is.
- I think a bug has to have, like, sucking mechanism
of something like, there's quite a lot of things
that you would think a bug's are not bugs.
Like if you ask Erika McAllister, for instance.
- Yeah, right.
- So he could have creepy crawlies as a...
- Or mini beasts.
- Mini beasts, in huge phrase they is.
Okay, so he's got even more of those,
but he's got 864 insect tattoos
on his body, his name's Michael Amoyah,
and he's quite a famous guy, actually.
He peers on a lot of, he's big on YouTube and so on.
- It is a bit of a trend, doesn't it?
Getting the most tattoo X variety on you.
So there's a guy who's got the most Marvel comic book hero tattoos.
- Oh yeah.
- And it starts with one, and then it just snowballs from there.
- Yes.
- You know, so this guy's got 63 superheroes all over him.
He's called Tom Radford, let him hull.
And he says, "I've endured pain in places,
"very few will understand, for tattoos no one will ever see,
"all for the sake of this record."
- Oh.
- But his head and neck and hands are completely uncovered.
Can you guess why?
- Yes.
- Head and neck and hands.
- Yep.
- He doesn't have any.
- He doesn't have a head or neck or hands.
- Right.
- That was going to be my guess.
- I didn't have the head that he fell on,
and there's no point having a neck.
(all laughing)
- Does he work in a place where he can cover up the rest
of his body quite easily, but can't cover his hands and neck?
- What kind of place would that be?
- Strip club.
- That strip club is the one place it wouldn't be
because strip clubs you literally are showing the rest
of your body.
- Yeah, that'll be the monster.
(all laughing)
- So you do like sign language for children's TV shows?
- That's brilliant girls.
I mean, it doesn't want to be confusing.
- Yeah.
- No, it's that he promised his mother he wouldn't.
- Oh.
- Okay, well, we were never going to guess that.
- Why weren't you going to guess that?
- Two more guesses I would have got there, I don't know.
(all laughing)
- So we...
- Yeah, that's cool.
- The most tattooed woman in Britain,
also she said he was a few years ago, Becky Holt.
I just find it really interesting
that her first tattoo was her boyfriend's name,
and it was on her crotch.
I just think that's such an interesting place
to get your first tattoo.
- Yeah.
- Usually your first tattoo would be...
- Um.
- Um, you know, belly.
On my family, it's just like this girl's going
on to bigger things tattoo-wise, isn't it?
- What if her boyfriend was called Fanny,
which is like short for Francis like Fanny Lee?
- Mm-hmm.
- So she could write a Fanny down there
and then future Bifrens wouldn't know it was the next Bifren.
They'd be like, "Oh, you just labeling your butt."
- That's what it was.
(laughing)
- Yeah.
- That's actually a really funny record to break
as the most parts of your body clearly labeled
with what they are in tattoo form.
Headshot as knees toes you start with and Fanny.
- Yeah.
- 'Cause that's the second verse of the song.
(laughing)
- I started looking up excuses for tattoos.
- Okay.
- Mainly Nazi tattoos.
- Because there are a lot of times where people
you've become obsessed with tattoos,
that they, you know, and then they go
onto a position of prominence, like podcaster.
- Like podcaster.
(laughing)
- Okay, his one.
- Yeah, go on.
- I thought it was a Hindu symbol of peace.
- Ding, ding, ding.
This year, the Bansley Councilor for Reform UK
who was accused of having a swastika tattoo.
His wife explained it was due to a brief interest
in Buddhism as a young man.
- That makes okay.
- Tick.
- All right, there's another one.
- I'll give you the tattoo.
Okay, okay, okay.
- Swastika's on Japanese maps means a temple.
So someone tattooed an entire Japanese map
like an ordnance survey map on.
- And said my body is a temple.
(laughing)
- Specifically this bit with a swastika.
- Someone's tattooed an early Rudyard Kipling book cover
onto them because he had swastika's all over them.
Youngest person ever to win the Nobel Prize
for Literature as well, by the way.
- Love the way.
- Love the way back there.
- You can leave that on the table.
- Yeah, is it that?
- It's not.
- I wanted to tattoo the words my struggle on my forehead,
but my tattoo artist was German.
And I wrote mine camp instead.
- I'm gonna give you the tattoo.
And you have to give me a great excuse for it.
- Okay.
- There's a German big brother contestant some years ago
who was done for having an SS-timp symbol tattooed on his arm.
What was his excuse?
- Very well, that's also illegal in Germany, of course.
- And you mean, so it's the font really with the assos?
- Yes, everyone used to call him a
silly sausage.
(laughing)
- Which is what?
- SS actually, man, do you know that?
Hitler's silly sausages.
(laughing)
- The elite silly sausages, yeah.
- It was the sound that his favorite snake made.
- It's as bad an excuse as this.
- Think of the font.
What else is written in that font?
- Oh, kindness.
- Yes.
- He claimed that he was a fan of the band really is,
but had only got the second half of the band name tattooed on him.
- He could only afford two letters and he went for that.
- That's so good.
- He needs to get a best friend who's got the K.I.
Quickly, get your best friend to get the K.I. on.
- Yeah, I'll just give you the last one.
There was a Lee Mack fronted sky history reality series
about woodwork called The Chop.
- Oh, I remember that.
- It was a very short live series.
One of the reasons for which was that one of the contestants
turned out to have a tattoo on his face saying 88.
And that is a number often used by neo-narsis,
because H is the eighth tattoo of the alphabet, HH,
HILH Hitler is the third. - Ah, right.
- He explained when challenged that this tattoo was simply
because his father had died in 1988.
At which point it turned out his father was alive and well.
- Yeah. - I told the Daily Mail,
"I'm here, aren't I?" (laughing)
- Wow. - Yeah.
- There's an interesting new tattoo that people are getting.
So every bit of content that goes up on Spotify
gives a little barcode, and it's meant to be
for just the actual code. - Share and playlists.
- Yeah, exactly.
So you could get your favorite episode of No Such Thing
as a Fish, find the barcode, have that tattooed on you,
and then if you do, it's just an option, as all I'm saying.
But this is happening. (laughing)
Listen to this, this is amazing,
'cause people are talking about having done it.
Mary Haley has the perfect party trick,
a barcode-like tattoo of nearly two dozen fine lines
that when scanned with a Spotify music app,
prompts a phone to play "Mambo No. 5" by Lou Babyhead.
(laughing)
- That was worth studying.
- Spotify have said, "Listen, great idea, very cool."
But if the song gets taken down and re-uploaded,
the code is changed, and that's a defunct barcode,
and a lot of people are also saying that when you get a bit older,
after a couple of years,
and the tattoo slightly loses a bit of its edge,
it has a bit of work to do. - It has a bit of work.
- It just ends up buying a tin of beans or something.
(laughing)
The US Navy in the early 1900s,
when certain people were coming and trying to join,
they were required to get more tattoos before they joined.
It's a little riddle, but I'll just give the answer straight away.
- No, no, no, no, no, we have to guess.
- Okay.
- So what use would be a tattoo for someone in the Navy?
- 'Cause they did have, they were a good deal.
- An anchor, good anchor tattoo.
- Yeah, but that's not useful, as you wouldn't need that.
Unless it was, maybe it could show who's on your side.
- Yeah, that's it. - Mm-hmm.
- Identify marks if you're washed up.
- That's a good one.
- And it's possible that maybe there was areas
where they did ask you to do that.
This very specific case was you were fixing things.
- Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
- Sailers in the Navy have to learn how to do a lot of knots.
And you learn how to do them by diagrams, don't you?
This is how to do a triple-chank-garf hitch, whatever.
So they're getting drawings of the knots tattooed on them, right?
- Yeah.
- To learn-- (laughing)
- Not right.
- What do you get?
- Right.
- As you get to see, zebrafish.
So they were tattooing zebrafish onto their arms.
But if you scan them, it's a cut for their favorite spotify.
- That's the place, man, but number five.
(laughing)
- And that's the International Distress Call.
That's what you know, if you hear it,
you know that someone's in serious trouble.
(laughing)
- The answer is that, these are all great answers, by the way,
but the one in this case is that a lot of sailors
who were joining in the early 1900s had tattoos
that were seen as indecent.
They had naked women all over them.
And so they would either be dismissed and not allowed
or you had to go back and have clothes tattooed
onto the women.
- Yes, because I read an interview with a tattoo artist
from the 1920s.
And it's interesting how things go in and out of fashion.
It was in the New Yorker and it was saying how fashionable
and classy tattoos suddenly were.
And this amazing tattoo artist was saying,
I have to put a lot of clothes on mermaids
for sailors who are about to go to the Indian Army
and out of many more.
- I went on to Guinnessworldrecords.com
and searched for ironic 'cause this world record holder
for most bug tattoos is terrified of bugs.
So the world record for sticking matchsticks up your nose
is held by Scott Consale, who worked in ER.
That was his job before beating the record.
And he says, over time your nostril stretch
so you can insert more matches into each side
if you wait a few minutes.
- I want to personally say,
I don't think you should shove anything up your nose.
- Absolutely.
- The first album by Westlife produced five number one hits
in the UK official singles chart, which is a record.
Ironically, the album peaked at number two.
- Wow.
- Wow, that's a pretty ironic, richly ironic.
Why didn't I get in the song?
- The Grand Midway Hotel in Windberg, Pennsylvania
has the world's largest Ouija Baud.
It's now located on the third floor of the hotel,
which is ironic because the inventor of the original Ouija Baud
William Fold died after falling from a third story building.
(laughing)
- And when you send out these lyrics
to Alana Sarsach for the rewrite.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, that's it.
That is all of our facts.
Thank you so much for listening.
If you'd like to get in contact with any of us
about the things that we have said over the course
of this podcast, we can all be found online.
I'm on @Streiberland on Instagram.
James.
- My Instagram is no such thing as James Harkin.
- Andy.
- My name's Andrew Honda M.
- Yep.
- And if you want to get to us as a group, Anna.
- You can email podcast@QI.com or on Instagram.
Go to @nosuchthing.
- That's right, podcast@QI.com.
That is the main place to go send us your mail
because if you send us your favorite facts every Monday,
we put down our facts and we read out the best of yours.
And if you also wanted to give us general feedback
and he cherry picks the best and brings those emails
to drop us a line.
The bonus behind the scenes show that we make,
which is part of Club Fish,
which is a really cool club that we've set up.
It's on patreon.com/clubfish.
If you want to check it out,
there's multiple different things, multiple tiers.
So give it a go, check it out.
Otherwise, do come back next week.
We're going to be back with another episode.
Thank you as ever to Lee and Lee,
Ethan, Rupert Ralea,
as well as the larger Fish Buster team for all their work.
And we will see you again next week.
Good luck.
(upbeat music)